Hey guys, I had another question from
someone relating to magnesium. She
wanted to know why I'm recommending
potassium so much but not magnesium.
Well, because potassium is probably the
number one uh deficiency of all the
minerals, but magnesium comes in number
two. So, let's talk about this one. Um,
we get a lot of calcium, but we don't
get a lot of magnesium primarily because
we don't consume enough vegetables. At
the heart of chlorophyll is the
magnesium mineral. And guess where we
get chlorophyll? In the vegetable.
That's all the greens. Okay. So,
magnesium is a co-actor for hundreds of
enzymes. It's a helper factor that helps
in the metabolism of energy, in the
metabolism of making proteins, hair,
nails, skin, muscle, and also helps the
heart rhythm. Okay. Um, it affects blood
pressure. So if you have high blood
pressure, this would help you. Um
increasing muscle tone, muscle cramps in
your calves, take some magnesium goes
right away. It will help you absorb
vitamin D. So magnesium helps balance
calcium. So they work as a teeter
totter. So let's say you have too much
calcium, you have arthritis, spurring,
little osteophittes that that go into
the joints. More magnesium will help
bring that down. Also, magnesium is
great to lower stress. It's good for
sleeping. Also, if you're constipated,
people take magnesium, but you get it
from leafy greens and a lot of the
vegetables. It's in nuts, it's in eggs,
it's in a lot of different foods, but
primarily I I would recommend getting it
from the greens. Men need 400 to 420
milligrams. Women need 310 to 320
milligrams. Okay? Again, most people are
not getting enough because they have
small salads. What causes a deficiency?
Excess calcium, especially if you're
taking like uh a calcium carbonate in
large amounts. That'll just deplete your
magnesium. Uh alcohol, sugar, refined
flour or grain products, and low stomach
acids because it takes acid to pull that
mineral into your body. So, how do you
know if you have low stomach acids? If
you get gas, indigestion, heartburn,
gird, then we know you have low stomach
acids. So, apple cider vinegar is really
good to take to help you absorb that
right there. Magnesium deficiencies are
also linked to insulin resistance
and this is why we recommend consuming a
lot of vegetables because you have the
potassium and magnesium to help reduce
insulin resistance and help correct that
problem. Also, it's great for headaches.
So, again, try to keep your vegetables
between 7 and 10 cups every single day.
Thanks for watching. Hey, if you haven't
already subscribed, press the button
below and I will keep you in the know.
Hey, that rhymes.